Lyle Swann is a champion off-road racer. But to the people of
1877, he's something very, very different...
Timerider: The Adventure of Lyle Swann is a science
fiction, western film directed by William Dear.
Lyle Swann is a successful off-road racer who
mistakenly gets sent back in time 100 years.
When a band of outlaws robs Swann of his motorcycle, he's forced to outfox the
gangsters and give in to the seductions of a gorgeous local lady.
With only his smarts and a map from an Exxon station, Lyle must try to make it
out of the Old West alive and find a way back to modern times.
Lyle Swann, played by Fred Ward.
Porter Reese, played by Peter Coyote.
Ben Potter, played by L.Q. Jones.
Carl Dorsett, played by Tracey Walter.
Claude Dorsett, played by Richard Masur.
Claire Cygne, played by Belinda Bauer.
Timerider: The Adventure of Lyle Swann is a 1982 American science fiction Western film directed by William Dear and starring
Fred Ward as Lyle Swann, a cross country dirt bike racer in the 1980s who is mistakenly sent back in time to 1877.
The film was scored, produced and co-written (with
director William Dear) by Michael Nesmith.
The film explores themes of mexico, experiment, time travel, revenge, shootout.
The tone is thought_provoking.